

Andreas Klein

Agile Coaching & Development

COLOGNE, GERMANY / +49 173 8888 987 / ANDY@IXIS.IO / WWW.IXIS.IO

Figuring out how to get Things done in larger Teams as a <u>certified</u> <u>Scrum Master</u>, not just in the software Industry. I help Agencies and Companies to realize Products with Value and with a Focus on happy People. I also enable <u>Conferences</u> to share Experiences.

Outside of the web, I'm a proud father of two beautiful children, a passionate freestyle skateboarder/snowboarder and I like the taste of good espresso.

If there is still time, I write on my personal blog http://ixis.io about things of the Internet.

My other Profiles on the web:



twitter.com/ixisio



github.com/ixisio



xing.com/andreas klein156

Skills

- · Agile mindset
- Professional Scrum Master® (PSM)
- Scrum Product Owner (PSPO)
- Moderation
- Agile Coach & Mentor
- Scaling Scrum with multiple Teams
- Change Management for Agile Product Development Teams
- · Frontend Development and Consulting
- Design Thinking
- · Workshops, Trainings and Coaching
- Kanban
- Continuous Improvement

Project Experience

AXA AG // Digital insurance products

Customer: AXA AG

· Role: Agile Coaching, Scrum Master

• Date: 2019

http://www.vaillant-group.com

Vaillant Group // Connected Devices - IoT, Websites

Customer: Vaillant Group Business Services GmbH

· Role: Agile Coaching, Scrum Master

Date: 2017 - 2018

http://www.vaillant-group.com

Toom Baumarkt // Websites & Shops

Customer: Rewe Group, Fork GmbHRole: Agile Coaching, Frontend Architect

• Date: 2016

· Technologies: Scrum, ES6, React.js

https://www.toom.de/

Aktion Mensch // Accessibility Workshop, Training

• Customer: Aktion Mensch e.V., Trusted Shops GmbH

• Role: Workshop Speaker

• Date: 2016

Topics: Accessibility

https://www.aktion-mensch.de/ http://www.trustedshops.de/

Billiger-Mietwagen.de // React Application

· Customer: Billiger-Mietwagen.de, SilverTours GmbH

Role: Front-End Architect

• Date: 2016

Technologies: React.js

https://www.billiger-mietwagen.de/

.. Ask me if you want to see the years 2009 to 2015.

Work Experience

| 2016 - present | Agile Coaching & Development (Freelance) www.ixis.io |
|----------------|---|
| 2009 - 2016 | Front-End Developer (Freelance) www.ixis.io |
| 2011 - 2014 | Frontend Developer (nexum AG) www.nexum.de |
| 2009 - 2011 | Application Developer eLearning (German Sport University Cologne) www.dshs-koeln.de |

Education

2008 - 2011 Study of Physics - University of Cologne (until 2009)

Magisterium

Study of Sports and Performance - German Sport

University Cologne *Bachelor of Science*



Cologne, last updated 01 September 2019, Andreas Klein